Richard Hendriks

Programmer

Contact

Website richardhendricks.example.com

(912) 555-4321

Email richard.hendriks@mail.com

About

Phone

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinal!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

Twitter SoundCloud

neutralthoughts dandymusicnl

Work Experience

Pied Piper

CEO/President Dec 2013 - Dec 2014 piedpiper.example.com

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores[™] that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Volunteer

CoderDojo

Teacher

Jan 2012 - Jan 2013

coderdojo.example.com

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

· Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

Education

University of Oklahoma

Jun 2011 - Jan 2014

ou.edu

- DB1101 Basic SQL
- CS2011 Java Introduction

Skills

Web Development

Master

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript

Compression

Master

- Mpeg
- MP4
- GIF

Languages

English

Native speaker

Interests

Wildlife

- Ferrets
- Unicorns

References

It is my pleasure to recommend Richard, his performance working as a consultant for Main St. Company proved that he will be a valuable addition to any company.

— Erlich Bachman